Harpreet Singh

Thornville Avenue, Dublin 5

□ (+353) 83 848 8767 | singhh@tcd.ie | www.harpreet.me | classingh | classingh

Summary _

Recently graduated from Trinity College Dublin with an M.Sc. in Computer Science with Distinction. Demonstrated capability of working in a team, in order to deliver high quality software. I want to employ my skill set in a Software Engineering role to further my knowledge and expertise.

Education ____

Trinity College Dublin

Dublin, Ireland

M.Sc. Computer Science, Networks and Distributed Systems

Sep. 2015 - Sep. 2016

• Graduated with Distinction

• Grade: 73%

University of Delhi

New Delhi, India

B.Sc. Physical Sciences

July 2012 - June 2015

• Graduated with First Class Honours

• Grade: 75%

Research ____

Postgraduate Research Dissertation, Trinity College Dublin

Dublin, Ireland

Proactive Configuration of Data Centre Networks

Apr. 2016 - Sep. 2016

- The Research was aimed at optimizing data centre networks for Big Data processing applications, specifically Hadoop, in Proactive manner using Software-Defined Networking.
- Proactive flow scheduling was evaluated on the basis of the network throughput achieved and job completion times of **Hadoop** jobs running in a **16 host cluster** emulation.
- Development was done using **Python**, while **Git** was used for source control.

Experience _____

Teaching AssistantDublin, Ireland

School of Computer Science and Statistics, Trinity College Dublin

Oct. 2016 - Present

- Currently working as a Teaching Assistant for two Masters programmes in Computer Science.
- Duties such as assisting students with their programming assignments, taking tutorials for certain lectures, assisting marking of assignments and tests under the supervision of the lecturer concerned.
- Coordinating a team of demonstrators for an undergraduate module in Distributed Computing.

Software Engineering Group Project, Trinity College Dublin

Dublin. Ireland

www.zooop.xyz

Dec. 2015 - Mar. 2016

- Zooop was a finalist at the **Citibank upStart Programme 2016**. It is a platform that let's food vendors push real time advertisements to an Android application from a Web portal.
- Developed a Web Application and an Android Application using **Test-Driven Development** and **Agile Methodologies** in a group of four developers.
- Web application was developed using **AngularJS**, **MongoDB** and **Node.JS**, while the mobile application was developed for **Android** using **Java**.

Networked Applications Project, Trinity College Dublin

Dublin, Ireland

www.organisr.xvz

Jan. 2016 - Mar. 2016

• Organisr is a platform that enables instructors of amateur sports clubs to organize training sessions.

• Developed a Web Application using Facebook Graph API, MongoDB, Node.JS and AngularJS in a group of 5 developers, which was deployed on Heroku.

Individual Programming Project, Trinity College Dublin

Dublin, Ireland

https://github.com/etSingh/P2PChatServer

Oct. 2015 - Dec. 2015

- Using **UDP Sockets**, developed a Peer-to-Peer Chat Server based on the *Pastry routing protocol*.
- Acquired extensive experience of developing applications with Ruby and using Git for version control.

Undergraduate Final Project, University of Delhi

New Delhi, India

Obstruction Avoiding Arduino Robot

Jan. 2015 - Apr. 2015

- Designed an autonomous robot using the **Arduino Microcontroller** which avoided obstructions in its path by using an Ultra-Sonic sensor.
- Gained experience of Embedded programming using **C**.

Skills

Programming Python, Ruby, Java, Node.JS, C/C++, C#, LaTeX

Web Express with Node.JS, AngularJS, MongoDB, HTML5, CSS

Tools Git, Vim, Linux, Docker **Languages** English, Hindi, Punjabi

Extracurricular Activities

'Ankur' Theatre Society, University of Delhi

New Delhi, India

Assistant Director of a Street Play

July 2012 - March 2014

• Responsible for managing and creatively driving a cast and crew of 20 people of a street play production of which was critically appreciated in the Delhi University Theatre Circuit and won numerous competitions.

Awards

INTERNATIONAL

3rd Position, "Quanta, the annual International Competition in Science"-Designed a model motor boat that was made to race among-st other competitors in a swimming pool, with schools from **16 different countries** participating.

Lucknow, India

DOMESTIC

2010

Michelle's Cup, Awarded for being the best all-rounder student of St. Jude's School.

Dehradun, India

References _____

Prof. Stefan Weber

032 Lloyd Institute Trinity College Dublin Stefan.Weber@scss.tcd.ie